©
© P @ rM ! nder
© P @ rM ! nder M @ nkÖÖ
© P @ rM ! nder M @ nkÖÖ ™
© P @ rM ! nder M @ nkÖÖ ™ Mobile - + 919815899536
Show yourself !
I know you 're out there .
( exclaims )
( ROARS )
( GASPS )
Help !
Help me !
( GRUNTlNG )
Somebody help me !
Help !
Alas ! Poor Yorick .
I knew him , Horatio .
A fellow of infinite jest , of most excellent fancy .
He hath borne me on his back a thousand times ,
and now , how abhorred in my imagination it is !
My gorge rises at it .
Here hung those lips .. .
( PEOPLE laughing )
Excuse me .
This is a private party , miss .
My name is Gwen Conliffe , and I 'm engaged to your brother , Ben .
is Ben here ?
No .
I 'm afraid no one knows where Ben is , which is why I 'm here .
Clive .
Well , boys and girls , let 's repair to the tavern !
Good night , sweet prince .
I seem to recall , Miss Conliffe .. .
I seem to recall he mentioned you in one of his letters .
And it 's quite uncharacteristic of my brother
to treat a lady in such a way ,
but the character of man is such a shiftable thing .
You misapprehend me . Benjamin is missing from Blackmoor .
He 's gone .
Did my father send you ?
No , I 'm here on my own .
It 's been nearly a month since anyone has seen Ben ,
and we knew that you were in London .
I 'd hoped you had received some word .
Why do you think he 's in trouble ?
Because the night he went missing , two villagers were killed .
Would you help us ?
Miss Conliffe ,
I am under contract for the next 30 performances .
If this is about your father , I know how you feel .
Do you ?
My company leaves for America tomorrow .
I simply can 't help .
He is your brother .
Good night .
It must be a wonderful luxury ,
doing battle with imaginary demons , Mr. Talbot .
Mine right now are very real .
Your mother ?
Yes .
My oldest memories of my mother ,
we are gathering grapes in her father 's vineyard .
It is my Garden of Eden .
You 're paying yours a visit ?
No , my mother died not long after this was made .
My father and my brother , they live near Blackmoor .
A man needs a good stick on the moor .
I purchased this one in Gévaudan lifetimes ago .
It 's the work of a master silversmith .
Would you do me the honor ?
It 's beautiful .
It will give me great pleasure to know that
it was the keeping of a civilized man .
Its heft is somewhat too much for me these days .
You 're overly kind .
But I 'm afraid I must refuse it .
As you wish .
( DOOR creaking )
Hello ?
( birds twittering ) ( wings fluttering )
( SNARLlNG )
Samson !
Lawrence ?
Hello , Father .
Ah .
Lo and behold , the prodigal son returns .
I hope you 're not expecting the fatted calf .
( SAMSON GROWLS )
Stay !
We don 't have many visitors .
You seem well .
I 've often wondered what you look like .
You 've come about your brother , have you ?
Stay .
Yes .
Miss Conliffe learned that I was in London .. .
( SAMSON continues growling )
Samson .
... and sent me a letter
saying that Ben has disappeared .
I thought I 'd offer my help in any which way I can .
Yes , what a splendid idea , Lawrence .
A splendid idea .
Too late , I 'm afraid .
Unfortunately , your brother 's body
was found in a ditch by the priory road yesterday morning .
I assume you have something to wear for the funeral .
Sir John . You remember my son , Lawrence ?
Singh , my servant .
Master Lawrence .
It 's nice to see you , Lawrence .
It 's good that you 're here .
Has Miss Conliffe been notified ?
Mmm-hmm .
She 's upstairs in her bedroom , asleep .
( piano playing )
Where are they keeping Ben 's body ?
Your father instructed me to bury your brother 's effects with him .
It seems a shame .
Thank you .
I wouldn 't , sir. lt 's .. .
I missed his whole life .
( PEOPLE laughing )
MONTFORD : What if it wasn 't a beast at all , but a cunning murderer ?
Someone who bore a grudge against one of these men .
To misdirect the authorities , he kills the men ,
and then he tears up the bodies
to make it look like a wild beast was responsible .
Ridiculous ! Who would go to such lengths ?
What about that gypsy dancing bear ?
It could have done it .
( SCOFFS ) That mangy thing ?
Kill three men ? I doubt it .
I saw the bodies with my own eyes .
Unnatural wounds .
Most unnatural .
Made by a fell creature , I say .
Damn gypsies wandering the countryside ,
bringing their woe and deviltry with them .
They show up , and two weeks later this happens !
My guess is Ben Talbot went to their camp
to have it off with a gypsy whore .
The bear gets hold of him ,
and they dump what 's left of him in the ditch !
Got nothing to do with the gypsies .
Twenty-five years ago now ,
me Pa found him .
Quinn Noddy and all his flock .
Brains and guts and God-knows-what
lying all over the moor for a quarter mile .
And , Quinn , the look on his face .
Like he 'd been eaten alive .
Whatever did it was big , had claws ,
and didn 't mind a load of buckshot .
After that , me Pa went home and ..
.. melted down me Ma 's wedding spoons
and cast silver bullets on them .
Wouldn 't leave the house on a full moon from then on .
He thought it was a werewolf .
I still say that bear 's to blame .
You 'd think the Talbots would 've learned their lesson , eh ?
Consorting with the Romas .
Right . Remember that black-eyed Salome the old man married ?
Went crazy up there in the ward , killed herself .
She was a gypo whore queen or some such , wasn 't she ?
LAWRENCE : Yes .
She was crazy
for coming to this shithole you call a town .
What did he say ?
You 're in your drink , boy .
Get him out of my tavern , Nye !
Come on , lad .
If you want to do something about it ,
I 'll be outside .
My mother wasn 't a whore .
Lawrence Talbot ?
( indistinct chattering )
Good evening .
Please join us. lt 's good to see you up and about .
Refreshed , recovered and as enchanting as ever .
Please , join us .
Good evening , Miss Conliffe .
Good evening .
What a pleasant surprise .
May I recommend the baked eel ?
Singh has outdone himself this evening , haven 't you , Singh ?
Something plainer .
Thank you .
I was a moment ago telling my son
that the telegraph system does reach us here in lonely old Blackmoor .
Do you find your home much changed , Mr. Talbot ?
Blackmoor does seem rather the same as I left it .
How so ?
The villagers , they still have the same wild ideas .
Yes , well , they 're a provincial lot , I must say ,
ignorant and superstitious to a worldly man such as yourself .
We 're savages at the ends of the earth .
I didn 't intend to start a squabble .
All I 'm saying is that you dismiss the natural man at your peril .
That 's all .
I find your insecurities quite strange , Father .
No , you mistake that for my self-awareness .
And how comfortable are you in your skin , may I ask ?
One can get used to anything .
Excuse me .
You know , Lawrence , I 've never understood what it is that you do ,
pretending to be other people .
But I understand you 're highly celebrated and famous for it .
Perhaps one day I 'll see for myself what all the fuss is about .
I think your mother would 've liked that .
She loved you and your brother with all her heart .
Why did she do it ?
She struggled with life , as we all do .
She lost .
Does that answer your question ?
I saw Ben 's body today .
What kind of animal could have done such a thing ?
I 've seen the work of a Kodiak bear and a Bengal tiger ,
nature at its most vicious ,
but I must say , I 've never seen anything like this .
People in town say it was a man .
( CHUCKLES )
You mean a raving lunatic at loose on the moor ?
Yes , it 's possible , but I think I would have run him down with my dogs .
On the other hand ,
the wounds are so terrible that only something human
would seem capable of such wanton malevolence .
I found a strange medallion among Ben 's belongings .
Yes , Saint Columbanus .
He was an Eastern saint .
He was also a gypsy .
So did Ben have dealings with the gypsies ?
Yes , he was our negotiator .
The local gentry would pay a fee ,
and the gypsies would keep their criminal activities to a minimum .
And they would move on once they 'd sold the local lads all the wine
and dark-haired ladies they could stand .
" That orbèd maiden with white fire laden , Whom mortals call the moon ,
" Glides glimmering o 'er my fleece-like floor .. . ' '
" By the midnight breezes strewn . ' '
She exerts enormous power , doesn 't she ?
I wish things were different .
Never look back , Lawrence . Never look back .
The past is a wilderness of horrors .
Lawrence , I 'm glad you 're home .
( SOFT knocking ON DOOR )
Can I help you , sir ?
I was hoping to have a word with Miss Conliffe .
Just a moment , sir .
( DOOR opening )
Miss Conliffe .
My behavior was unacceptable .
These were Ben 's .
He 'd want you to have them .
If there 's anything you need , anything at all , please let me know .
I want to know what happened to him .
I 'll do everything I can .
Thank you .
Thank you for coming .
( children whispering )
( children giggling )
( laughing )
Mother !
YOUNG BEN : ( whispering ) Lawrence .
Lawrence .
( distant screaming )
( whispering ) Lawrence , wake up .
I heard something .
( whispering ) Lawrence .
Lawrence , I 'm scared .
Go back to bed .
( GROWLlNG )
Mother ?
Mother !
( THUNDER rumbling )
Hello . Hello .
Ben said that you played here as children .
It was our refuge .
From what ?
You mean from whom .
Your father ,
he has a way with being distant .
Ben told me it was because I reminded him of your mother .
He said you did , as well .
Which is why he put me in an asylum for a whole year ,
then shipped me off to my aunt in America .
sir JOHN : You sure you won 't stay one more night ?
My father has lodgings at the inn ,
and that 's more convenient for the train , so .. .
When do you return to London ?
Not till I find out what happened to my brother .
( whip CRACKS ) ( HORSE neighs )
Lawrence , that 's all well and good ,
but I think your inquiry could wait until tomorrow .
The moon is full tonight , and I 'd prefer that you stay inside
in the event that your raving lunatic theory is correct .
I don 't want to lose you , too .
( PEOPLE chattering )
( DOG barking )
Take your horse , sir ?
Good evening .
( speaking ROMANl )
He says you must stay in the camp .
The woods are not safe .
Ask him if he knows anyone who sells these .
BOY : You want to talk to Maleva .
To who ? Maleva .
It was found on my brother 's body .
Your caravan shows up , three men are killed .
I don 't think it 's a coincidence .
There is no coincidence .
Only fate .
But she plays a hidden hand .
Tell me about my brother .
( MEN clamoring )
( whistling )
MAN : Run round the back !
( ROARS )
( PEOPLE clamoring )
( MAN shouting lNDlSTlNCTLY )
Give us the bloody bear , you old snake handler .
We know what 's been going on .
Nonsense . He dances , that 's all .
( police whistle blowing )
Come on ! Get off !
What 's going on here ?
We 've come for the bear , Nye .
It done all the killing .
( sighs ) For goodness ' sake !
He 's harmless .
( roaring )
( MAN screaming )
( GURGLlNG )
( PEOPLE screaming )
( screaming )
What happened ?
It 's the Devil ! The Devil !
( HORSE neighing )
( ROARS ) ( SCREAMS )
Mama ! Mama !
Maria !
Maria ! Where are you , Maria ?
MAN : Over there !
Maria !
( GROWLlNG )
( screaming )
Mama !
Mama ! My baby .
Take the girl . Stay in the camp .
LAWRENCE : Boy !
Boy !
( wings fluttering )
( ROCK CLATTERS )
( GROWLlNG )
( LAWRENCE screaming )
( GUNSHOTS )
Go back , get help !
( gasping )
Get Maleva !
WOMAN : Once he is bitten by the beast , there is no cure .
You should let him die .
You would make me a sinner .
There is no sin in killing a beast .
is there not ?
( panting )
( speaking ROMANl )
Sometimes the way of fate is a cruel one .
He can only be released by someone who loves him .
( groaning )
( speaking ROMANl )
Whoa !
Lawrence .
Holy Mother of God .
Help me with him , Singh .
( coughing )
( GROWLlNG )
( gasping )
" Do thou but thine and be not diffident of wisdom
" She deserts thee not if thou dismiss not her "
is everything all right ?
( CLANKlNG )
Lawrence ?
Get Dr. Lloyd .
Are you all right ?
Yes , I feel better .
( WATER dripping )
I thought you were leaving .
Well , this place is impossible to escape .
Besides , it 's the least I could do .
What did the gypsies say ?
Some nonsense about the Devil being at Blackmoor .
It 's remarkable .
A week ago , I would have said you 'd never use that arm again .
And now ?
It seems to have healed itself .
I 'll be back to check on you at the end of the week .
Thank you , Doctor .
Miss Conliffe . Yes ?
I want to thank you .
For ?
For prolonging your stay here at Blackmoor with us during this difficult time .
Had there been some sense of filial obedience ,
well , you would not have been inconvenienced .
Well , Lawrence was trying to find out what happened to Ben .
And now we know it 's still out there .
Nevertheless , I thank you .
Not at all .
You should be asleep , Lawrence .
So should you .
is there anything I can get for you ?
Are you expecting a war ?
A Sikh is a warrior of God .
He must always arm himself against evil .
Do you believe in curses ?
This house has seen more than its share of suffering .
Your mother . Your brother .
Yes , I believe in curses .
How could you stand it here all these years ?
You didn 't have to stay .
Silver .
I didn 't know you hunted monsters .
Sometimes monsters hunt you .
Yes , he 's been quite seriously injured , Inspector ,
and he 's suffering from a loss of memory .
I don 't think he could be of any use to you now .
Well , I think , at some point ,
he is going to want to talk about .. .
No. I do understand .
Only if I could have just a few words with him .
No . A completely unofficial interview .
Even the briefest exchange could be infinitely helpful to me .
( SAMSON BARKS )
Francis Aberline , Scotland Yard .
Honored to meet you , Mr. Talbot. I 'm a huge admirer .
I 'm sorry to hear of your troubles .
I do hope they won 't impede your return to the stage .
Thank you .
Shall we ? Please .
LAWRENCE : It was an animal .
ABERLlNE : You 're quite sure ?
What else could it have been ?
There are other witnesses , no doubt , that had a better look than I did .
Well .. .
Not too good a look , I 'm afraid .
None of the locals survived to tell of it ,
and the gypsies only talk of demons and devils .
I understood your injury was quite savage .
Yes .
I hope you don 't find this prurient ,
but would it be possible for me
to arrange for a specialist to examine you ?
It 's amazing what we can discern by scientific means these days .
And at your convenience , of course .
Of course .
No , a great mystery , it is ,
given that there are no natural predators left in England
capable of inflicting such horrific injuries .
Well , the savagery of the attack would suggest the action of an animal .
Or a lunatic , perhaps .
Someone with a history of mental disturbance ,
who 'd spent time inside an asylum
and who may have suffered injuries at the hands of his victims .
I get your implication
and resent it .
You 're clearly aware of my personal history ,
as I believe I am aware of yours .
Weren 't you in charge of the Ripper case a couple of years back ?
Well , you 're a direct man , so I 'll be equally direct with you .
I 'm not your enemy , Mr. Talbot .
But you 've been seen as Hamlet , Macbeth , Richard lll ,
all with that same face .
Now a prudent man would ask who else might be living inside that head of yours .
Good day , Inspector .
So you won 't mind if I establish your whereabouts
on the nights in question ?
Feel free .
Good day , Mr. Talbot .
I 'll be sending my specialists to examine you
at your convenience , of course .
( ROARS )
Lawrence ?
Yeah . You all right ?
Yes .
What did the lnspector say ?
Well , he asked a lot of questions .
I 'm sorry. I feel so responsible for what 's happened to you .
If I hadn 't sent that letter , you 'd be back in New York .
No . No. lt was right that I came back .
You mustn 't feel like that .
No .
( giggling ) Try it .
Well , I can 't make it skip like you .
You have to flick it .
May I ? Yes .
When you throw it , turn your wrist up and whip it .
Wrist up and whip it .
And make sure you swing your hips .
( laughing )
What 's it like in New York ?
( HORSES neighing LOUDLY )
( giggling )
Did you hear that ?
What ?
Horses .
Hello , Doctor. I thought our appointment wasn 't till Friday .
Come with us. lt 's nearly the full moon .
You were bitten by the beast .
You bear his mark now .
STRlCKLAND : Mr. Talbot .
There are many of us here who are looking for a natural explanation .
Help us .
Come on , Talbot . Show us your wound .
We are told it heals in an unnatural way .
( HORSE snorting )
( NElGHlNG )
Get your hands off of me .
Will you let him murder your wives and children ?
( GUNSHOT )
( NElGHS ) ( exclaims )
( groaning )
MONTFORD : My eyes !
Damn you , Talbot !
Sorry , Colonel .
I meant to shoot you .
Sadly , I 'm not the marksman I
used to be I must be getting old .
He 's cursed . God has forsaken him .
Let us deal with him .
You know you 're trespassing on my land ,
and I could shoot you on the spot right now .
My Sikh manservant , he 's on the roof ,
and he happens to be a crack shot with a repeating rifle .
And he will kill you .
He 'll kill the next eight of you before he has to reload ,
so please take yourself off my land .
And if I see any of you trespassing this way again ,
I won 't be so civil , if you take my meaning .
Good day to you , Colonel .
Lawrence .
You 're bleeding .
How could they possibly think he 's a threat to them ?
Well , he 's a stranger here in Blackmoor , Miss Conliffe ,
and that makes him very dangerous .
Thank you .
Yes . You can also thank Singh when he returns from the village .
You 're not the only one in the family who can act .
Samson !
( SAMSON GRUNTS )
Let 's get something to clean that .
Did they hurt your shoulder ?
No .
On the contrary , it feels much stronger than before .
That 's good .
I was able to hold them .. .
All three of them back .
You know , you mustn 't listen to them . The villagers .
They 're backward and foolish .
Everything I hate about this place .
( HEART beating )
( whispering ) This might sting a bit .
Lawrence .
Excuse me .
( banging ON DOOR )
What 's happened ?
You have to leave .
Please pack your things .
Did I do something ?
It 's not safe here .
You must return to London tonight .
I 'll be out here waiting .
Lawrence , wait .
What are you afraid of ?
If anything ever happened to you ,
I 'd never forgive myself .
( driver URGES HORSE ) ( whip CRACKS )
REVEREND FlSK : There are those who doubt the power of Satan .
The power of Satan to change men into beasts !
But the ancient pagans did not doubt .
Nor did the prophets .
Did not Daniel warn Nebuchadnezzar ?
But the proud king did not heed Daniel .
And so , as the Bible says , " He was made as unto a wolf and cast out from men . ' '
A beast has come among us .
But God will defend his faithful .
With his right hand , he will smite the foul demon .
I say to you , the enemy 's ploy is a devious one .
Twisting the accursed into beasts , he seeks to bring us low .
Make us as animals .
Teach us self-loathing ,
so we forget that we are made in the image of Almighty God himself !
( GROWLlNG menacingly )
Samson .
( GROWLlNG )
Why does our Lord tolerate this mockery ?
" Pride goeth before destruction ,
" a haughty spirit before the fall . "
I say it is because we have sinned against him .
Because our crimes reek to heaven , and they demand vengeance .
( ALL chattering in LOW voices )
( CHATTERlNG STOPS )
Pint of bitter , please .
Mrs. Kirk .
Why aren 't you out with MacQueen , trying to catch that thing
what killed my husband ?
As I don 't know where the lunatic will strike ,
it seems the practical thing to do is to stay as near as possible
to the potential victims .
( MAN spitting OUT drink )
( coughing )
And seeing that 21 4 of the 309 residents of Blackmoor and its environs
live within , what , 500 yards of this tavern ,
I was planning to spend the evening here .
Not Talbot Hall ?
Why would you say that ?
They 're cursed , all of them .
Unfortunately , " cursed " does not give me a warrant
to wander about Sir John 's estate at night .
Rules , Mrs. Kirk .
They 're all that keep us from a dog-eat-dog world , you know .
Pint of bitter , please .
( HUMPHS )
Lawrence ,
Miss Conliffe has left Blackmoor .
Yes , I sent her away .
She 's probably in London by now .
Why would you do that , Lawrence ?
Because this place is cursed .
Father .
It is a shrine to your beloved mother .
She was truly a beautiful woman .
I know that losing her wounded you deeply .
And it is monstrous , a young boy seeing his mother like that .
And I would have given my life , Lawrence ,
that you hadn 't found us that night .
You must believe me when I tell you this , Lawrence .
You do believe me , don 't you ?
I loved your mother with a passion like the burning of the sun .
Her death finished me .
I was devastated .
I still prowl the house at night ,
searching for her .
I 'm dead all the same .
Look into my eyes , Lawrence .
You see , I 'm quite dead .
© P @ rM ! nder M @ nkÖÖ ™
My dear fellow , I wish I could tell you
that the tragedy that has beset your life was over .
But I 'm afraid the darkest hours of hell lie before you .
I don 't think they 'll kill you , Lawrence ,
but they will blame you .
The beast will have its day .
The beast will out .
( GRUNTS )
( KNUCKLES cracking )
( gasping )
( GRUNTlNG )
( groaning )
( GROWLlNG )
( roaring )
( MOANlNG )
( SNARLlNG )
( HOWLlNG )
( clamoring )
( HORSE neighing )
( GRUNTlNG )
( DEER BELLlNG )
We 've got him , men !
We got him !
Mind the pit , Johnny !
( EXCLAlMlNG )
Johnny ? Help me get out !
Shoot it ! Shoot him !
( GROWLlNG )
( screaming )
Johnny !
Johnny ?
( screaming )
MONTFORD : MacQueen !
( GUNSHOTS )
( screaming )
( GUN clicks )
( panting )
( WHlMPERlNG )
( DR. LLOYD screaming )
( screaming STOPS )
( SNARLlNG )
( HOWLlNG )
sir JOHN : ( whispering ) Lawrence .
Lawrence .
Lawrence !
Wake up .
Lawrence .
Terrible things , Lawrence .
You 've done terrible things .
( gasping )
( GUNSHOTS )
MAN : Hold your fire !
We want him alive !
Get down ! On your knees !
Ah , tis as you said , Inspector .
It is as you said .
I 'm sorry , Sir John .
sir JOHN : Be strong , Lawrence .
Be strong .
( DOOR slamming )
Where is my father ?
I am sorry to see you back here with us , Lawrence .
You disappoint me .
But we have made enormous strides
in the treatment of delusions such as yours .
Where is my father ?
( screaming )
Bracing , is it , guv 'ner ?
( exclaims WEAKLY )
( gasping ) Where 's my father ?
( shouting ) Where 's my father ?
Where is my father ?
( screaming )
I said if you don 't kill my father , he will kill again and again
and again and again .
( screaming )
" Prithee , Horatio , tell me one thing .
" Dost thou think Alexander looked o ' this fashion i ' the earth ?
" And smelt so ? And smelt so ? "
I hope this won 't impede your return to the stage .
Alas , poor Yorick !
YOUNG BEN 'S voice : Lawrence , wake up .
I heard something .
sir JOHN : Terrible things , Lawrence .
( DOOR creaking )
Terrible things .
( gasping )
Father !
( coughing )
( screaming )
Look into my eyes , Lawrence . You see , I 'm quite dead .
GWEN : It 's all right , Lawrence .
Everything 's all right. I 'm going to take you home .
Come with me .
It 's all right . Come on .
It 's all right .
Hold me .
Just hold me .
( ROARS ) ( GASPS )
Shh .
It 's not real .
( ROARS )
( METAL GEARS CLANKlNG )
sir JOHN : Lycanthropy .
Yeah , lycanthropy .
( lNHALES DEEPLY )
I contracted the disease , if that 's what it is , in India in the Hindu Kush .
The natives directed me to a cave high up in the mountains ,
where , according to legend , lived a strange creature .
A very strange creature .
And after a great many days of climbing and searching ,
finally , I came upon it. I found it .
I found the cave , and the strange creature that lived there .
It was a little boy ,
a little wild feral boy , powerfully strong ,
( SNARLlNG )
( CHUCKLES )
who suddenly attacked me and bit me .
So I returned to my hunting companions in the valley below
thinking I 'd been made the butt of a joke .
( CHUCKLES )
I soon discovered otherwise .
( SNARLS )
You killed my mother .
Yeah , I suppose I did .
You should kill yourself .
Oh , I cannot tell you how often I 've considered that .
But life is far too glorious , Lawrence ,
especially to the cursed and the damned
like myself .
Yeah .
Every night of the full moon ,
for many years , I 've been locked away in that crypt
by Singh , my faithful servant .
Twenty-five years .
( sighs )
Then she came , didn 't she ? Hot and burning like the face of the moon .
Gwen ?
Yeah , she would have taken your brother away from me ,
and they would have both vanished into the night forever .
And although I was resigned to it , the beast in me was not .
And , Ben , you understand , had come to tell me
that he was quite resolute in his decision to leave Talbot Hall for good
and to take Gwen away from me .
I became drunk and violent , and extremely violent .
And I struck out at Singh , who was trying to restrain me ,
( LAUGHS )
and I knocked him out cold .
Poor .. . Poor old Singh .
Yeah .
You know , I never told you this , Lawrence ,
but I used to be a bare-knuckle prize fighter
when I was a young man in the ports of Boston ,
San Francisco , New York .
Back in the good old days , before you were born .
Long time ago .
Bam !
Yeah .
Anyway , as a consequence , I was unable to lock myself in the crypt that night .
And I found your brother 's body in a ditch
not far from the house .
He 'd been torn to pieces .
I know now it was a mistake to lock up the beast .
Don 't you think so , Lawrence ?
I should have let it run free .
Kill or be killed .
I 'll kill you !
( GRUNTS )
You have a long way to go yet , my young pup .
I 'll kill you .
Oh your chance is coming
soon enough .
She 'll be full tonight ,
the moon .
I have a small gift for you , Lawrence ,
in the event you don 't find life
as glorious as I find it to be .
Or not to be .
I 'm deeply sorry about this , Lawrence .
I do love you , dear boy .
You may find that hard to believe ,
in the light of what has happened .
I 'll kill you .
Sleep now. I 'll kill you .
Rest .
Guard ? I 'll kill you !
LAWRENCE : I 'll kill you !
( playing harmonica )
( CHURCH BELL DlNGlNG )
DR. HOENEGGER : I attempted to remove these mental fabrications ,
but now , 25 years later , I find that young Lawrence 's harmless hallucinations
have manifested themselves into delusions of a horrific nature .
Ah !
Mr. Talbot .
( groaning ) We are here tonight to illustrate conclusively
that Mr. Talbot 's fears are quite irrational .
So we will remain in this room together ,
and once Mr. Talbot has witnessed
that the full moon holds no sway over him ,
that he remains a perfectly ordinary human being ,
he will have taken his first small step
down the long road to mental recovery .
( audience MURMURlNG )
Now , we are all aware that Mr. Talbot
has suffered quite traumatic personal experiences .
He witnessed his mother 's self-mutilations .
His young mind , unable to accept it , created a fantastical truth ,
that his father is to blame .
That his father is literally
a monster .
( audience MURMURlNG )
But your father is not a werewolf .
You were not bitten by a werewolf .
You will not become a werewolf
any more than I will sprout wings and fly out of that window .
( ALL laughing )
( MUFFLED ) Please , please , help me .
I think that Mr. Talbot has something to say to us .
( coughing )
( SOFTLY ) Stop it .
Speak up , Mr. Talbot .
Forgive me , but we can 't hear you .
You moron .
Tonight , I will kill all of you !
( ALL laughing )
I will kill all of you !
Yes , well , as you can see , lycanthropy
Please do something about it ! is a disease of the mind
existing somewhere in the deep recesses Kill me .
Kill me ! of Mr. Talbot 's thoughts .
( groaning ) To him , it seems very real .
( joints cracking )
The subject before you has , for the past month ,
undergone both pharmaceutical and physical desensitizing
( groaning ) in order to reduce the nervous exaggerations .
( GRUNTlNG )
( gasping )
( continues chattering lNDlSTlNCTLY )
( GROWLlNG )
Dr. Hoenegger ?
This malady derives from .. .
( GROWLlNG )
MAN : Doctor ! Doctor !
( ALL exclaiming )
Let me pass !
( ALL screaming )
MAN : For God 's sake , hurry up !
( screaming )
Open .. . Open this door !
It seems to be locked , sir .
( screaming )
Idiot ! Open it !
( shouting )
Smash open this door !
Help me !
( screaming )
( roaring )
( GROWLlNG SOFTLY )
( HOWLlNG )
Davis ? Yes , sir ?
Are you armed ? Yes , sir .
Give me your revolver ! Quickly !
( WOMEN EXCLAlMlNG )
( EXCLAlMlNG )
Pardon me . Excuse me .
As you were .
Carter ! Sir .
Have you got a pistol ? Yes , sir .
Follow me .
Telegraph the Yard .
Issue weapons .
All right , sir . Now !
Right away , sir !
I don 't suppose we have any silver bullets .
What ?
( WOMEN screaming )
( whistle blowing )
( screaming )
Clear the street !
( GROWLS )
( screaming )
MAN : Oh , my God !
You two , with me .
( ALL screaming )
Steady .
( HOWLlNG )
God help us .
( drinking )
( HORSE whinnies )
( HORSES CLOMPlNG OVERHEAD )
MAN 1 : Up ahead !
MAN 2 : Start checking the docks !
( police whistle blowing )
( THUDDlNG )
( SOFT moaning )
( THUDDlNG ) ( SOFT GASP )
( WOOD CREAKlNG )
Who 's there ?
Lawrence ?
( gasping ) What are you doing here ?
( GRUNTS )
What have they done to you ?
I am what they say I am .
I 'm a monster .
And so is my father .
He killed Ben .
And my mother , too .
I can help you .
There 's no help for me .
If such things exist ,
if they are possible ,
then everything is .
Magic .
And God .
I can find a way to stop it .
I must confess ,
I envy my brother for the days he had with you .
What joy he must have felt .
I would have given anything I own
to have known you in another life .
I must get back to Talbot Hall and end this .
Lawrence .
Please let me help you .
You already have .
Lawrence , don 't . Just stay here with me .
Stay here with me !
( knocking ON DOOR )
( knocking lNSlSTENTLY )
Miss Conliffe , good morning .
Inspector .
May I impose ?
I must ask you directly , have you seen Lawrence Talbot ?
I 'm sure by now you 've heard of his escape .
Yes , I 've heard . And , no , I haven 't seen him .
Miss Conliffe , I cannot stress to you enough the mortal peril you 're in
should you find yourself in his presence .
Thank you. I 'll be careful .
Miss Conliffe , I admire your noble intentions .
You think you can save him , but you can 't .
I must insist you come with me .
lnsist ? He 's not .. . Carter !
He 's not here , Inspector !
Take your hand off me .
Come on ! Take your hand off me !
Come on now , woman !
Talbot ?
Raise your arms and step out where l can see you .
No ! Come now ! Come along !
Now there 's some bad luck for you .
Globe ! Globe ! Lawrence Talbot is still missing !
Police scour London !
Globe ! Globe !
Lawrence Talbot is still missing !
Police scour London !
( speaking ROMANl )
I 'm looking for a woman called Maleva .
Do you know her ?
( speaking ROMANl )
Thank you .
Psst .
What is it you want from me ?
Lawrence Talbot .
You know what happened to him .
You understand it .
Listen to me .
I need you to help me .
Leave him to his fate .
I have to save him .
Do you love him ?
Just tell me what to do .
Will you condemn him ?
Or will you
set him free ?
Do you know what that means ?
Yes .
But I can 't. I can 't do that .
He 's still there .
I know he is .
I know I can save him .
I 'm begging you , tell me what to do .
There is no cure .
You are risking your life .
May the saints protect you and give you strength to do what you must .
driver : Whoa ! Whoa , there !
You 're sure he 'll come ?
Yeah , quite sure .
Right .
Take the priory road .
Railway station .
South garden to the river .
Tell Sir John we 're here ,
and then stay close to the estate ,
but not too close .
If you see Talbot ,
don 't get caught in a conversation .
Shoot him
and kill him .
On sight !
( DOOR creaking )
Carter hasn 't reported .
He 's not at his post in front of the house .
ABERLlNE : Miss Conliffe ?
Wait !
Get the others .
( wind moaning )
( WOOD CREAKlNG )
( barking )
( GROWLlNG )
( panting )
( GASPS )
( THUDDlNG )
( SAMSON barking )
Samson .
( playing RESUMES ) ( humming )
" l will arise and go to my father ,
" and I will say unto him , 'Father , I have sinned against heaven and before thee .
" ' l am no more worthy to be called thy son . ' "
( STOPS playing )
And lo and behold , there he stands .
The prodigal son .
For he is returned .
Shall I have my own robe brought to be placed upon your shoulders ?
Rings for your fingers ?
Shoes for your feet ?
What you should do is pray ,
but we both know it wouldn 't do any good .
( speaking Italian )
Are those Singh 's silver bullets in my gun ?
I 'm sorry .
You have me at a disadvantage .
It makes me happy .
What does ?
Seeing you here like this .
My son returned .
It is glorious , isn 't it ?
No. lt 's hell .
Hell ?
No . The beast is the beast .
Let it run free .
( GUN clicks )
( exclaims )
Poor little Lawrence .
You were the fragile one .
I removed the powder from those shells many , many years ago .
But I confess ,
I was quite overwhelmed by your enormous courage .
Finally , you 're the man I always wanted you to be .
Lawrence ! My boy .
Here .
Do you see her , Lawrence ?
Do you feel her presence ? Her power ?
She 'll be here soon .
Coming from darkness into light .
You 're heir to my kingdom , Lawrence .
( GROWLlNG ) You 've always been heir to my kingdom .
( NECK CRACKS ) ( GROANS )
( cracking )
( GROWLlNG )
( roaring )
( HOWLS )
( groaning )
( HOWLlNG in pain )
( screaming )
( HOWLlNG )
Lawrence .
Lawrence !
( GROWLlNG )
No !
( screaming )
Run ! Run !
( DOGS barking )
Are you sure you 're all right , sir ?
Go on .
( GROWLlNG )
( breathing SHALLOWLY )
( sniffing )
( roaring )
( GROWLlNG )
Look at me , Lawrence .
You know me .
You know who I am .
Don 't .
You know who I am !
Lawrence ! Don 't .
( GROWLlNG )
Look at me .
Lawrence , you know me .
You know me , remember me , look at me .
( GROWLlNG SOFTLY )
lt 's Gwen .
Lawrence , it 's Gwen . Please .
( GROWLlNG SOFTLY )
©
© P @ rM ! nder
© P @ rM ! nder M @ nkÖÖ